Finding Aid for Gunnar Birkerts papers 1930-2002
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Faculty Papers
  - University of Michigan Professor of Architecture, 1963-1992
    - Honors Design Studio Applicants' Resumes, Letters of Intent and Biographical Sketches
      - Graham Foundation Grant Studio, Fall 1971 (Box 11)
        [SR RESTRICTED until July 1, 2047 ]
      - Graham Foundation Grant Studio, Fall 1972 (Box 11)
        [SR RESTRICTED until July 1, 2048 ]
      - Fall 1983 (Box 11)
        [SR RESTRICTED until July 1, 2059 ]
      - Fall 1984 (Box 11)
        [SR RESTRICTED until July 1, 2060 ]
      - Fall 1985 (Box 11)
        [SR RESTRICTED until July 1, 2061 ]
      - Fall and Winter 1986-1987 (Box 11)
        [SR RESTRICTED until July 1, 2062 ]
      - Fall and Winter 1987-1988 (Box 11)
        [SR RESTRICTED until July 1, 2063 ]
      - Fall and Winter 1988-1989 (Box 11)
        [SR RESTRICTED until July 1, 2065 ]
    - Course Registers, Syllabi, Assignments and Related Materials
      - Architecture 522, Winter 1963 (Box 8)
      - Architecture 322 & 522, Fall & Winter, 1964-1965 (Box 8)
      - Architecture 422, Winter 1966 (Box 8)
      - Architecture 522, Fall & Winter, 1966-1967 (Box 8)
      - Architecture 522, Fall & Winter, 1968-1969 (Box 8)
      - Architecture 522, Fall & Winter, 1969-1970 (Box 8)
      - Architecture 692, Fall & Winter, 1970-1971 (Box 8)
      - Graham Foundation Grant Design Studio, Fall & Winter, 1971-1972 (Box 8)
      - Graham Foundation Grant Design Studio, Fall & Winter, 1972-1973 (Box 8)
      - Architecture 692, Winter 1974 (Box 8)
      - Architecture 672/692, Fall 1974 (Box 8)
      - Architecture 672, Winter 1977 (Box 8)
      - Architecture 500, 552 & 562, Fall & Winter, 1977-1978 (Box 8)
      - Architecture 562/612, Fall & Winter, 1978-1979 (Box 8)
      - Architecture 562, Winter 1980 (Box 8)
      - Architecture 672/692, Fall & Winter, 1980-1981 (Box 8)
      - Architecture 672/692, Fall & Winter, 1981-1982 (Box 8)
      - Architecture 672, Fall 1982 (Box 8)
      - Architecture 672/692, Fall & Winter, 1983-1984 (Box 8)
      - Architecture 672/692, Fall & Winter, 1984-1985 (Box 8)
      - Architecture 672/692, Fall & Winter, 1985-1986 (Box 8)
      - Architecture 672/692, Fall & Winter, 1986-1987 (Box 8)
      - Architecture 672/682, Fall & Winter, 1987-1988 (Box 8)
      - Architecture 672, Fall & Winter, 1988-1989 (Box 8)
    - Thomas S. Monaghan Architect-in-Residence Professorship, 1984 (Box 8)
    - Professor Emeritus of Architecture, May 1990 (Box 8)
    - Faculty Activities Records, 1972-1988 (Box 8)
    - Correspondence, 1980-1995 (Box 8)
  - University of Oklahoma Bruce Alonzo Goff Professor of Creative Architecture, 1990-1993
    - Course Materials, 1990 (Box 8)
    - Correspondence, 1990-1993 (Box 8)
    - Press Release and Newspaper Article, 1990 (Box 8)
  - Lawrence Technological University Visiting Professor of Architecture, 1992-1993
    - Reflective Practice Studio Schedules, 3/93-5/93 (Box 8)
    - Correspondence, 1992-1993 (Box 8)
    - Press Releases, 1993 (Box 8)
- Project Files
  The Project Records series of the Gunnar Birkerts collection contains the architect's textual files and conceptual drawings associated with 122 of the buildings and projects which he has designed over his 50-plus-year career. Unlike the Gunnar Birkerts and Associates Collection, which houses all of the records and drawings associated with fourteen of his firm's buildings, the Gunnar Birkerts Collection is significant for its highly personal representation of the architect's creative process. This last series in the collection brings together over 1800 sketches in his own hand, many documenting the moment of a building's conception on tracing paper, shirt cardboard or the memo pad of an Italian hotel. In Birkert's words:
  That is the moment that I call the organic synthesis -- when all the factors affecting the personality of the building come together in the right magnitudes and the building starts to grow like a plant. The first drawing isn't necessarily pretty, but after you analyze it you see that everything the building needs is in it because it was created by your mind - which as full of everything you needed to know. Sometimes I call these drawings "blobs," but they are really the representation of my brainwaves. An architecture critic would call them seminal ideas. [Gunnar Birkerts, Gunnar Birkerts: Process and Expression in Architectural Form (Norman: University of Oklahoma Press, 1994), 34.
  Birkerts' textual and visual project records are arranged by building in chronological order from the time of his association with Eero Saarinen in the 1950s through the turn of the twenty-first century. The conceptual sketches and schematic design and design development drawings in the collection are described individually, and 282 of them are linked in this finding aid to online digital images scanned from 4x5 color transparencies of the original drawings. Researchers can click on the "view image" link next to the descriptions of these drawings in the to access these images of 58 of Birkerts; buildings. This will open an new browser window and display the image stored in the Bentley Historical Library Image Bank. It is also possible to search the Image Bank Directly. Birkerts retained the originals of a number of the conceptual drawings. Descriptions of these items are provided in the contents list with a link to a digital copy.
  - Furniture Design Series #5203-5204 for August Grasis, 1952
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Design Development Drawings., undated; Pencil drawings on tracing paper and vellum
        - Plan and Elevations of Chair (#5203), 23x32 inches (Map-case 1, Folder 1)
        - Plan and Elevation [of Table] (#5204)., 18x36 inches (Box 1, Folder 1)
        - Plans, Elevations and Details [of Table] (#5204)., 20x29 inches (Box 1, Folder 1)
        - [Plans and Details of Table], untitled., Three drawings, 13x18 to 18x29 inches (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - General Motors Technical Center, Warren, Michigan Eero Saariinen Office Project, 1950s
    - Project Files
      - Photographs of stair detail and interiors, Two 3x3-inch photographs of stair details and six 7x5-inch photographic negatives of interiors drawings by Birkerts (Box 9)
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Schematic Design Drawings by Gunnar Birkerts of Staircase Designed by Kevin Roche, circa 1954
        - [Staircase Perspective], untitled., undated; Two blue-line prints and one sepia print, 30-1/2x35-1/4 to 31-1/2x41 inches (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Eero Saarinen Office Projects, Bloomfield Hills, Michigan, 1950s
    - Project Files
      - General Motors Research Isotope Laboratory., One 8x10-inch photograph of Initial First Floor Plan and one 2x2-inch photographic negative of stairs (Box 9)
      - Milwaukee War Memorial, One 8x10-inch photograph of building model, one 8x3-inch photograph of interior perspective, and one 3x3-inch photograph of north stair (Box 9)
      - University of Michigan North Campus Master Plan., Two 8x10-inch photographs of study drawing and site plan (Box 9)
  - Furniture Designs for Yellin, Inc., 1953-1954
    - Project Files
      - Photographs, 1953-1954; Five 8x10-inch black-and-white photographs (Box 9)
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Series # 5302-5318
        - Design Development Drawings, Pencil drawings on vellum and tracing paper 7/10/53 except as noted
          - Plug Detail (#5302), undated; 18x22-3/4 inches (Box 1, Folder 2)
          - Details of Coffee Table (#5309), 31x37-1/2 inches (Box 1, Folder 2)
          - Side Elevation and Plan [of Chair] (#5310), 34-1/2x43-1/4 inches, initialed, revised 2/7/54 (Box 1, Folder 2)
          - Details for Upholstered Seat & Back [of Chair] (#5310), Initialed, 29-1/2x36 inches, revised 2/7/54 (Box 1, Folder 2)
          - Front and Rear Elevations [of Chair] (#5310), 32-1/2x42-1/4 inches, revised 2/7/54 (Box 1, Folder 2)
          - Side Elevation & Plan [of Chair] (#5312), 34-1/2x42-1/2 inches (Box 1, Folder 2)
          - Front Elevation [of Chair] (#5312), 31-1/4x45-1/4 inches (Box 1, Folder 2)
          - Details of Juvenile Version of Design 5312 (#5312-J), 09/01/1953; 29-1/2x36 inches (Box 1, Folder 2)
          - Details of Chair (#5313), Two drawings, 34x51-1/2 & 34-1/2x45-1/2 inches (Box 1, Folder 2)
          - Plan [of Chair] (#5313), 33-1/2x38-1/2 inches (Box 1, Folder 2)
          - Details of Stool (#5314), 36x44-3/4 inches (Box 1, Folder 2)
          - Details of Bar Stool (#5318), 09/01/1953; 36-1/4x43-1/2 inches (Box 1, Folder 2)
          - [Details of Chair], untitled., undated; Three drawings, 25-1/2x36 to 36x43 inches (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Table Group
        - Design Development Drawings of Table Group. Pencil and ink drawings on vellum, except as noted
          - Details of Table Leg, 02/12/1954; 27x36 inches (Box 1, Folder 2)
          - Plans, Elevations and Sections of A Group of Low Tables, 02/15/1954; 24-1/2x36 inches (Map-case 1, Folder 2)
          - Plan and Elevations of Step Table, 04/17/1954; 18x28-1/4 inches (Map-case 1, Folder 2)
          - Plan and Elevations of End Table, 04/17/1954; 18x28-1/2 inches (Map-case 1, Folder 2)
          - Plans and Elevations of Corner Table 1 & #2, 04/17/1954; 18x28-1/2 inches (Map-case 1, Folder 2)
          - Plans and Elevations of Round and Square Cocktail Tables, 04/17/1954; 18x28-3/4 inches (Map-case 1, Folder 2)
          - Plan, Elevations and Details of "Doughnut Table.", 04/17/1954; 18x30-1/2 inches (Map-case 1, Folder 2)
          - Details of End Corner of Step Tables, 04/17/1954; 18x30-1/4 inches (Map-case 1, Folder 2)
          - Plan and Elevations of Oblong Cocktail Table, 05/17/1954; 18x30-1/2 inches (Map-case 1, Folder 2)
          - Plan and Elevations of Oval Cocktail Table, 05/19/1954; 18x30 inches (Map-case 1, Folder 2)
          - Plan and Elevations of Bench, 05/20/1954; 18x30-1/4 inches (Map-case 1, Folder 2)
          - [Elevation of Table], untitled, undated; 10-1/4x18 inches (Map-case 1, Folder 2)
          - [Plan, Elevations and Perspective of Table], untitled, undated; 20-1/2x27-1/2 inches (Map-case 1, Folder 2)
  - Furniture Design, 1954
    - Project Files
      - Photographs of Sven's Chair, 1954; Ten 2x3-inch black-and-white prints (Box 9)
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Design Development Drawings of Chair, 5/9/54, except as noted, Pencil--on-vellum drawings
        - Partial Plan. Two drawings, one untitled, undated; 18x24 & 15x18 inches (Map-case 1, Folder 2)
        - Front Elevation, 17-1/2x28 inches (Map-case 1, Folder 2)
        - Side Elevation. Two drawings, 18x23-1/2 inches (Map-case 1, Folder 2)
        - [Elevations], untitled, undated; Pencil drawing on reverse of blue-line print, 18-3/4x35-3/4 inches (Map-case 1, Folder 2)
      - Design Development Drawings of Furniture for Edward Alden Studios, Pencil-on-vellum drawings, 20x36 inches
        - Partial Plan and Elevations of Convertible Stool., 11/16/1954 (Map-case 1, Folder 2)
        - Plan and Elevations of Occasional Chair., 11/19/1954 (Map-case 1, Folder 2)
  - International Furniture Competition and Exhibition, Cantu, Italy, 1955-1956
    - Project Files
      - Correspondence, 1955-1957 (Box 9)
      - Exhibition Catalog, 1955 (Box 9)
      - Newspaper Articles, 1955 (Box 9)
      - Photographs, 1 prints black and white 7x9-inch; 1 prints black and white 5x5-inch (Box 9)
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Design Development Drawings of Office Furniture, undated; Blue-line prints
        - Partial Plan, Elevations and Section [of Chair], 2 prints pencil sketches on blue-line prints 21-1/4x30-1/2 and 21-1/4x29-1/2 inches (Map-case 1, Folder 3)
        - Partial Plan, Elevations and Section [of Sofa], 20-1/2x29 inches (Map-case 1, Folder 3)
        - Plan, Elevations, Sections and Details of Desk, 21x29-3/4 inches (Map-case 1, Folder 3)
        - Plan, Elevations and Details of Chair, 21x29 inches (Map-case 1, Folder 3)
        - Elevations [of Table], 20-3/4x29 inches (Map-case 1, Folder 3)
        - Plans, Elevations and Sections of Work and Typing Tables, 20-1/2x32 inches (Map-case 1, Folder 3)
        - Elevations, Sections and Details of Bookshelves and File Cabinet, 21-1/2x29-3/4 inches (Map-case 1, Folder 3)
      - Construction Drawings. 9-3/4x14-inch photostatic prints of drawings, undated
        - Plan and Elevations of Chair, 2 prints (Map-case 1, Folder 3)
        - Elevations and Plans of Supporting Frame for Chair and Arm Chair (Map-case 1, Folder 3)
        - Plan, Elevation and Details of Tea Table (Map-case 1, Folder 3)
        - Plan, Section and Details of Chess Table (Map-case 1, Folder 3)
        - Plans and Side Elevation of Chess Table (Map-case 1, Folder 3)
        - Plan, Elevations and Section of Serving Trolley (Map-case 1, Folder 3)
        - Plan, Elevations, Sections and Details of Magazine Rack (Map-case 1, Folder 3)
  - Mequon House, Mequon Wisconsin. Winner of Progressive Architecture Design Award, (unbuilt project), January, 1957
    - Project Files
      - Architect's Conceptual Statement (Box 9)
      - Newspaper Article, 1957 (Box 9)
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Conceptual Sketches., Undated
        - [Sketch], untitled, 8x9-1/4-inch photographic print of ink sketch (Map-case 1, Folder 4)
      - Design Development Drawings. undated, except as noted, 11x14-inch photographic and 8-1/2x13-3/4-inch photostatic prints of drawings
        - [Living Room Perspective], untitled (Map-case 1, Folder 4)
        - West Elevation., 05/07/1956 (Map-case 1, Folder 4)
        - North-South Section, East-West Section and South Elevation., 2 prints (Map-case 1, Folder 4)
  - Aluminum House, Virgin Islands (unbuilt project), 1958
    - Project Files
      - Newspaper Articles, 1958-1959 (Box 9)
  - Troyton Manor Swimming Club, Troy, Michigan (unbuilt project), 1960
    - Project Files
      - Newspaper Articles, 1960-1961 (Box 9)
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Schematic Design Drawings., Undated
        - [Site Plan], untitled, Pencil-on-vellum drawing, 15x36 inches (Map-case 1, Folder 4)
  - Roosevelt Competition, Roosevelt Island, New York, New York (unbuilt project), 1960
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Conceptual Sketches., Undated
        - [Early Sketch], untitled, Red crayon sketch on yellow, lined paper, 8-1/2x11 inches (Map-case 1, Folder 4)
        - [Early Sketch], untitled, Blue ink sketch on yellow paper, 8-1/2x11 inches (Map-case 1, Folder 4)
        - [Site Plans], untitled, Black crayon and blue pencil sketches with green pencil coloring on six sheets of tracing paper, 12x21 to 24x41 inches (Map-case 1, Folder 4)
        - [Site Plan Studies], untitled, Pencil and colored pencil sketches with crayon coloring on eleven sheets of tracing paper, 12x13-1/2 to 12x46 inches & 24x37 inches (Map-case 1, Folder 4)
        - [Sketch], untitled, Black crayon sketch on tracing paper, 12x19 inches (Map-case 1, Folder 4)
        - [Drawing], untitled, Pencil drawing on vellum, 18x19-1/4 inches (Map-case 1, Folder 4)
  - Haley Funeral Home, Southfield, Michigan, 1960-1961
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Schematic Design Drawings. Pencil and colored pencil drawings on vellum, 18x24 inches, except as noted, undated
        - [Early Site Plan], untitled. Initialed (Map-case 1, Folder 5)
        - [Early Floor Plan], untitled. Initialed (Map-case 1, Folder 5)
        - Plot Plan. Pencil and dot screen on vellum (Map-case 1, Folder 5)
        - Main Floor Plan (Map-case 1, Folder 5)
        - Basement Plan, One pencil on vellum drawing and one pencil drawing on blue-line print with notations (Map-case 1, Folder 5)
        - Revised First Floor Plan (Map-case 1, Folder 5)
        - Exterior Elevations, Two drawings, one with dot screen (Map-case 1, Folder 5)
  - Albion Church (Grace Lutheran Church), Albion, Michigan (unbuilt project), 1960
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Schematic Design Drawings., Undated
        - [Floor Plan and Elevation], untitled, Pencil and colored pencil drawing on vellum, 24x36 inches. (Map-case 1, Folder 5)
  - Schwartz Summer Residence, Northville, Michigan, 1960-1962
    - Project Files
      - Architect's Conceptual Statement (Box 9)
      - Newspaper Articles, 1960-1961 (Box 9)
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Design Development Drawings by Gunnar Birkerts., Undated
        - [Elevations], untitled, One pencil drawing on tracing paper, 12x21-1/2 inches, and three pencil drawings on vellum, 18x24 to 17-1/4x36-1/4 inches (Map-case 1, Folder 6)
      - Preliminary Construction Drawings by Gunnar Birkerts, except as noted, Pencil-on-vellum drawings
        - [Floor Plan], untitled., 02/04/1960; 26x36-1/4 inches (Map-case 1, Folder 6)
        - Sections (#5). 24-1/2x36-1/4 inches, 02/16/1960 (Map-case 1, Folder 6)
        - Roof Framing Plan (#6) by Frank Straub., 02/16/1960; 25-1/4x36-1/4 inches (Map-case 1, Folder 6)
      - Construction Drawings by Frank Straub except as noted, 03/10/1960; Pencil-on-vellum drawings, 24x36-1/4 inches
        - Title Sheet and Site Plan., Undated (Map-case 1, Folder 6)
        - Foundation Plan and First Floor Framing (#2) (Map-case 1, Folder 6)
        - Roof Framing Plan (#3) (Map-case 1, Folder 6)
        - Floor Plan (#4) (Map-case 1, Folder 6)
        - Elevations (#5) (Map-case 1, Folder 6)
        - Sections and Details (#6 & 7) (Map-case 1, Folder 6)
        - Kitchen Plan and Elevations and Interior Elevations (#8) (Map-case 1, Folder 6)
        - Reflected Ceiling Plan (#9) (Map-case 1, Folder 6)
        - Fireplace Details (#10) (Map-case 1, Folder 6)
        - Interior Design [Floor Plan]., 05/19/1960 (Map-case 1, Folder 6)
        - [Elevation and Details], untitled., Undated (Map-case 1, Folder 6)
      - Supplemental Construction Drawings., Undated
        - [Structural Details], untitled, Pencil and red pencil notations on two blue-line prints, 18x24 inches (Map-case 1, Folder 6)
  - University Reformed Church, Ann Arbor, Michigan, 1960-1964
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Conceptual Sketches. Undated, except as noted
        - [Sketches], untitled, Blue and red ink and pencil sketches on three sheets of tracing paper, initialed, 12x13-1/4 to 12x23-1/4 inches (Map-case 1, Folder 6)
        - [Studies], untitled, Blue ink and pencil sketches on seventeen sheets of yellow paper, 8-1/2x11 inches, one dated 5/1/62 (Map-case 1, Folder 6)
        - [Studies of Lighting Fixtures], untitled, Blue ink sketches on two sheets of yellow loose-leaf paper, 8-1/2x11 inches (Map-case 1, Folder 6)
      - Schematic Design Drawings., undated; Pencil and colored pencil drawings on tracing paper, 12x26-1/2 to 12x30-1/4 inches
        - [Early Site Plan], untitled. Initialed (Map-case 1, Folder 6)
        - [Early Floor Plan], untitled, Two drawings, one initialed (Map-case 1, Folder 6)
  - Erieview Towne Plaza Apartment Competition, Cleveland, Ohio (unbuilt project), 1961
    - Project Files
      - Newspaper Articles, 1961-1962 (Box 9)
  - 1300 Lafayette East Apartments, Detroit, Michigan, 1961-1963
    - Project Files
      - Architect's Conceptual Statement (Box 9)
      - Newspaper and Journal Articles and Press Release, 1960-1973 (Box 9)
  - Kaufman Residence, Muskegon, Michigan (unbuilt project), 1962
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Conceptual Sketches., Undated
        - [Early Sketch], untitled, Blue ink sketch on yellow loose-leaf paper, 8-1/2x11 inches (Map-case 1, Folder 6)
        - [Early Sketches], untitled, Ink and red pencil sketches on three sheets of yellow paper, 8-1/2x11 inches, and one piece of shirt cardboard, 8x14 inches (Map-case 1, Folder 6)
  - People's Federal Savings and Loan Bank, Branch Office, Royal Oak, Michigan, 1962-1963
    - Project Files
      - Architect's Conceptual Statement (Box 9)
  - Furniture Designs for Birkerts House, Bloomfield Hills, Michigan, 1961-1962
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Construction Drawings, Pencil-on-vellum drawings, 24x36 inches
        - Elevations of Sofa and Club Chair. Initialed, 12/06/1961 (Map-case 1, Folder 7)
        - Plan, Elevation, and Details of Coffee Table. Initialed, 01/28/1962 (Map-case 1, Folder 7)
        - Plan and Leg Detail of Coffee Table. Initialed, 01/31/1962 (Map-case 1, Folder 7)
        - Elevations of Desk., Undated (Map-case 1, Folder 7)
  - Ash-Stevens Research Laboratory, Detroit, Michigan, 1962-1963
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Conceptual Sketches. Undated, except as noted
        - [Sketches], untitled, Ink sketches on two sides of yellow University of Michigan envelope, 6-3/4x9-1/2 inches (Map-case 1, Folder 7)
        - [Sketches], untitled, 05/22/1963; Ink sketches on reverse of University of Michigan College of Architecture and Design Executive Committee Meeting Minutes, 8-1/2x11 inches (Map-case 1, Folder 7)
        - [Sketches], untitled, Ink sketches on two sheets of yellow paper and seven sheets of yellow loose-leaf paper, 8-1/2x11 inches (Map-case 1, Folder 7)
        - [Elevations and Axonometric], untitled, Purple and black crayon and ink sketches on four sheets of tracing paper, 12x19 to 12x23-1/4 inches (Map-case 1, Folder 7)
  - Furniture Designs, 1960s
    - Project Files
      - Photographs, Twelve black-and-white photographic prints and four negatives of assorted sizes, and eighty-two 35 mm. negatives (Box 9)
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Design Development Drawings., Undated
        - [Elevations and Plan of Leather and Steel Lobby Seating], untitled, Brown pencil drawings on two sheets of tracing paper, 9-3/4x21-1/4 & 8-1/2x21-1/2 inches, and one 7x5-inch photographic negative (Map-case 1, Folder 7)
        - [Elevations and Plans of Leather and Steel Lobby Seating], untitled, Brown pencil and pencil drawing on three sheets of tracing paper, 18x31 inches, and one pencil drawing on reverse of blue-line print, 26-3/4x28 inches (Map-case 1, Folder 7)
        - [Perspectives of Leather and Steel Lobby Seating], untitled, Brown pencil drawings on two sheets of vellum, 11-1/2x14-1/2 inches (Map-case 1, Folder 7)
        - [Perspective of Glass and Steel Table], untitled, Green pencil and pencil drawing on tracing paper, 9-3/4x17-1/2 inches. (Map-case 1, Folder 7)
        - [Perspectives and Details of Glass and Steel Table], untitled, Green pencil and pencil drawings on nine sheets of tracing paper and one sheet of vellum, 12x24 to 23x33-1/2inches (Map-case 1, Folder 7)
  - International Village, Detroit, Michigan (unbuilt project), 1964
    - Project Files
      - Newspaper Articles and Brochures, 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Bald Mountain Recreation Area Facility, Pontiac, Michigan, 1964-1969
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Conceptual Sketches., Undated
        - [Early Sketches], untitled, Ink sketches on two sides of shirt cardboard, 8x12 inches (Map-case 1, Folder 8)
        - [Early Sketches], untitled, Ink sketches on two sides of six pieces of shirt cardboard, 8x12 to 8x14 inches (Map-case 1, Folder 8)
        - Entrance Booth, Comfort Station, Bath House and Concession Stand, Ink sketches on shirt cardboard, 8x12 inches (Map-case 1, Folder 8)
  - Elmwood Housing, Detroit, Michigan (unbuilt project), 1964
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Conceptual Sketches., Undated
        - [Sketch], untitled, Purple crayon sketch on tracing paper, 12x25 inches (Map-case 1, Folder 8)
        - [Sketches],untitled, Blue ink sketches on yellow loose-leaf paper, 8-1/2x11 inches (Map-case 1, Folder 8)
        - [Sketches], untitled, Blue ink sketches on yellow loose-leaf paper, 8-1/2x11 inches (Map-case 1, Folder 8)
        - [Sketches], untitled, Black ink sketches on yellow loose-leaf paper, 8-1/2x11 inches (Map-case 1, Folder 8)
        - [Sketches], untitled, Blue and black ink sketches on sixteen sheets of yellow loose-leaf paper, 8-1/2x11 inches (Map-case 1, Folder 8)